Register of the Sir Karl Raimund Popper Papers, 1928-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE I, 1932-1987
  - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft, 1979 (Box 363, Folder 1)
  - Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft, 1975 (Folder 2)
  - Wissenschaftskolleg zu Berlin (Peter Wapnewski), 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Witschel, Gunter, 1984 (Folder 4)
  - Witte, Paul de, 1979 (Folder 5)
  - Witwatersrand University Press, 1983 (Folder 6)
  - Woitschach, Max, 1978 (Folder 7)
  - Wold, Herman O., 1967-1968 (Folder 8)
  - Wolf, A., 1946 (Folder 9)
  - Wolf, George, 1949 (Folder 10)
  - Wolff, Michael, 1970 (Folder 11)
  - Wollheim, Richard, 1967-1978 (Folder 12)
  - Wolters, Gereon, 1983 (Folder 13)
  - Woo, Henry K. H., 1985 (Folder 14)
  - Wood, Christopher C., 1985 (Folder 15)
  - Wood, Lady Muriel E., 1946-1949 (Folder 16)
  - Woodger, J. H., 1938-1953 (Folder 17)
  - Woodrow, Peter J., 1983 (Folder 18)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1973 (Folder 19)
  - Woods, Bill, 1976 (Folder 20)
  - Workers' Book-Guild. See Sifriat Poalim
  - World Congress of Philosophy (Deyan Pavlov, Alain Diemer, Andre Mercier), 1972-1978 (Folder 21)
  - World Congress of the International Federation of Catholic Medical Associations (Gian Luigi Gigli), 1982 (Folder 22)
  - World Perspectives, 1966 (Folder 23)
  - Worrall, John, 1975-1978 (Folder 24)
  - Wouk, Herman, 1978-1981 (Folder 25)
  - Wright, Georg Henrik von, 1947-1975 (Folder 26)
  - Wright, Stephen J., 1977-1980 (Folder 27)
  - Wroblewski, Mr., 1959 (Folder 28)
  - Wuketits, Franz M., 1980-1981 (Folder 29)
  - Yabrov, Alexander A., 1978-1984 (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Yale Review, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Yale University (George Schrader), 1968 (Folder 3)
  - Yamagishi, Takeshi, 1968 (Folder 4)
  - Yamey, B. S., 1960 (Folder 5)
  - Yanase, Michael Mutsuo, 1984 (Folder 6)
  - Yasui, Takuma, 1977 (Folder 7)
  - Young Liberals, 1983 (Folder 8)
  - Young Men's Christian Associations National College (Stephen Woodhams), 1982-1984 (Folder 9)
  - Yourgrau, Palle, 1967-1968 (Folder 10)
  - Yourgrau, Wolfgang and Thella.
    Includes correspondence with Allen D. Breck, Wilbur C. Miller, and Robert L. Wadlinger
    - 1959-1969 (Folder 11)
    - 1970-1978 (Folder 12)
  - Zahar, Elie G., 1977-1984 (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Zalud, Paul, 1964-1968 (Folder 2)
  - Zander, Michael, 1977 (Folder 3)
  - Zander, Walter, 1958 (Folder 4)
  - Zanitti, L.(?), 1960-1961 (Folder 5)
  - Zapatero, J. C., 1970 (Folder 6)
  - Zarnikow, Hans, 1980-1982 (Folder 7)
  - Zechner, Leopold, 1965 (Folder 8)
  - Zeh, H. D., 1979 (Folder 9)
  - Zeisel, Hans, 1981-1984 (Folder 10)
  - Zeit (Fritz J. Raddatz), 1982-1984 (Folder 11)
  - Zelger, Josef, 1973-1978 (Folder 12)
  - Zenker, Gert, 1981-1985 (Folder 13)
  - Zentralbibliothek fur Physik in Wien (Auguste Dick), 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Zeppelin, Annette von, 1936 (Folder 15)
  - Zhou, Jun-jie, 1984 (Folder 16)
  - Ziegler, Lothar J., 1977-1982 (Folder 17)
  - Zilk, Helmut, 1982-1983 (Folder 18)
  - Ziman, John M., 1982-1984 (Folder 19)
  - Zimmerman, E. J., 1966 (Folder 20)
  - Zippelius, Reinhold, 1977-1984 (Folder 21)
  - Zober, Martin, 1951 (Folder 22)
  - Zollinger, Heinrich, 1978 (Folder 23)
  - Zollschan, George K., 1956-1966 (Folder 24)
  - Zschorner, Helmut, 1982-1983 (Folder 25)
  - Zuckerman, Solly, 1963-1969 (Folder 26)
  - Zweites Deutsches Fernsehen, 1981-1983 (Folder 27)
- COURSE MATERIAL, 1937-1970 (Boxes 366-382)
  Correspondence, examination questions, memoranda, notes, roll lists, and syllabi, arranged alphabetically by university
  - Canterbury University College, Christchurch, New Zealand
    - General
      - Comments from students, 1945 (Box 366, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, including with the University of New Zealand, London Office
        - General, 1939-1945 (Folder 2)
        - Re appointment, 1936-1937. (Folder 3)
          Includes Karl Popper's curriculum vitae, as well as a circular entitled "Schedule of Duties and Conditions of Appointment of a Lecturer in the Department of Education and Philosophy"
        - Re leave of absence and resignation, 1945-1946 (Folder 4)
        - Re Professor Sutherland, 1940-1944 (Folder 5)
        - With Henry Hudson re the latter's notes and remarks (included) on Rudolf Carnap's Logical Syntax (Folder 6)
      - Examination questions (for "Logic" and "Ethics"), 1941-1945. (Folder 7)
        Includes a student paper
      - Mark sheets (for "Logic" and "Ethics"), 1945 (Folder 8)
      - Notes, 1945-1946 (Folder 9)
      - Report of research in progress, 1943 (Folder 10)
      - Suggestions for the proposed reform of the syllabus in philosophy and psychology (Folder 11)
      - Summary of Karl Popper's address (entitled "Some Comments on the University of New Zealand and Comparisons with European Universities") at the discussion of university problems by the council and staff, 1945 September 6 (Folder 12)
    - Lectures
      - "Economic History." Reading list and syllabus (Folder 13)
      - "Ethics"
        - General (Folder 14)
        - Notes, 1945 (Folder 15)
        - Syllabus, 1939 (Folder 16)
      - "Logic"
        - General (Folder 17)
        - Notes, n.d. (Folder 18)
        - Syllabi, 1939-1941. (Folder 19)
          Includes "Notes for Symbolic Logic," by Rudolf Carnap
      - "Religion: Some Modern Problems and Developments" (Karl Popper made four of the 12 presentations in this discussion course: A, 10). Syllabus, 2, 7, 8 n.d. (Folder 20)
    - Seminar on the Viennese Circle. Notes, 1937 (Folder 21)
  - Canterbury Workers' Educational Association (W.E.A.), Christchurch, New Zealand. "Science in the Making"
    - Notes, n.d. (Folder 22-23)
    - Syllabus, 1941 (Folder 24)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University, California. Outline of program, 1956-1957 (Folder 25)
  - Harvard College, Cambridge, Massachusetts. "Philosophy." Miscellany, See also Northwestern University, 1950. (Folder 26)
  - Institute of Advanced Studies, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia. Seminar series on "Induction,", 1963
    - Notes (Box 367, Folder 1)
    - Typewritten transcript
      - First (seminar) (Folder 2)
      - Second (Folder 3)
      - Third (Folder 4)
      - Fourth (Folder 5)
      - Fifth (Folder 6)
      - Sixth (Folder 7)
      - Seventh (Folder 8)
      - Eighth (Folder 9)
      - Ninth (Folder 10)
  - London School of Economics, England
    - General
      - Circulars, 1943-1968 (Box 368, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - General, including with Walter Adams, Sydney Caine, Alexander M. Carr-Saunders, D. V. Glass, H. Kidd, C. A. Moser, and H. C. Scriven
          - Undated (Folder 2)
          - 1946-1957 (Folder 3)
          - 1958-1969 (Folder 4)
        - Re examinations, including with the Civil Service Commission and the Local Government Examinations Board, 1946-1965 (Folder 5)
        - Re faculty appointments, 1957-1965 (Folder 6)
        - Re research assistance, 1959-1969 (Folder 7)
        - Re students, 1947-1968 (Folder 8)
        - With the Library, 1954-1966 (Folder 9)
      - Examination questions (for "Logic" and "Scientific Method") (Folder 10)
      - Examination regulations (Folder 11)
      - Mark sheet, n.d. (Folder 12)
      - Minutes.
        Includes agenda of meetings
        - Appointments Committee, 1952-1965 (Box 369, Folder 1)
        - Board of Philosophical Studies, 1952-1965 (Folder 2)
        - Board of Studies in Economics, 1965 (Folder 3)
        - Board of Studies in the History of Science and Technology and the Philosophy of Science, 1947-1965 (Folder 4)
        - Professorial Council, 1946-1947 (Folder 5)
      - Miscellany (Folder 6-7)
      - Notes by Karl Popper
        - Undated. (Folder 8)
          Includes "Note on the Role of Philosophy in Undergraduate Courses"
        - (for lectures and seminars on "Logic" and "Scientific Method"), 1946-1955 (Folder 9)
        - 1947-1950 (Folder 10)
        - (on probability), 1956 May-July (Folder 11)
        - (for lectures and seminars on "Problems of Philosophy" and "Scientific Method"), 1965-1966 (Folder 12)
        - (for lectures and seminars on "Social Philosophy," "Philosophy of the Social Sciences," and "Scientific Method"), 1968-1969 (Folder 13)
      - Proposal for an extension of the teaching activities of the Department of Philosophy, Logic and Scientific Method (Box 370, Folder 1)
      - Reading lists and syllabi (Folder 2)
      - Reading material (Folder 3-4)
      - Reports on some of Karl Popper's seminars, 1951-1953 (Folder 5)
      - Statement of development policy (of the Department of Philosophy, Logic, and Scientific Method), 1964 (Folder 6)
    - Lectures
      - "Introduction to Scientific Method." See "Scientific Method"
      - "History of Logic Since ? Paradoxes" (sic). Syllabus, 1958 (Folder 7)
      - "Logic"
        - General (Box 371, Folder 1)
        - Examination questions, See also General, Correspondence, Re examinations, 1945-1966. (Folder 2)
        - Mark sheets, 1946-1947 (Folder 3)
        - Notes, n.d. (Folder 4)
        - Syllabi
          - 1946-1947 (Folder 5)
          - 1948-1949 (Folder 6)
          - 1954-1955 (Folder 7)
          - 1955-1956 (Folder 8)
          - 1958 May (Folder 9)
          - 1958-1959 (Box 372, Folder 1)
          - 1959 October-December (Folder 2)
          - 1960 October 10 (Folder 3)
      - "Philosophical Problems"
        - Notes, 1967 October (Folder 4)
        - Syllabi, 1967 October-December (Folder 5)
      - "Philosophy of the Social Sciences"
        - General (Box 373, Folder 1)
        - Syllabi
          - 1960
            - May (Folder 2)
            - June (Folder 3)
          - 1968 October-November (Folder 4)
      - "Problem of Derivation and Proof." Syllabus (Folder 5)
      - "Problems of Philosophy"
        - Student comments (Folder 6)
        - Syllabi, 1965
          - October (Folder 7)
          - November (Folder 8)
          - December (Folder 9)
      - "Scientific Method"
        - General (Box 374, Folder 1)
        - Examination questions.
          - Undated (Folder 2)
          - 1946-1948 (Folder 3)
        - Notes
          - Undated (Folder 4)
          - 1963-1964 (Folder 5)
          - 1964-1965 (Folder 6)
          - 1966-1967 (Folder 7)
        - Syllabi
          - 1948-1950 (Folder 8)
          - 1954 October-November (Folder 9)
          - 1955
            - February-May (Folder 10)
            - October-December (Folder 11)
          - 1956 January-May (Folder 12)
          - 1958-1959 (Box 375, Folder 1)
          - 1959 October-December (Folder 2)
          - 1960 October (Folder 3)
          - 1961
            - February-May (Folder 4)
            - December (Folder 5)
          - 1962 January (Folder 6)
          - 1963 October-December (Box 376, Folder 1)
          - 1964
            - January-May (Folder 2)
            - October-December (Folder 3)
          - 1965
            - January-March (Box 377, Folder 1)
            - October (Folder 2)
            - November (Folder 3)
            - December (Folder 4)
          - 1966
            - January (Box 378, Folder 1)
            - February (Folder 2)
            - March (Folder 3)
            - October-November (Folder 4)
          - 1967
            - February (Box 379, Folder 1)
            - March (Folder 2)
            - May (Folder 3)
          - 1968 October-November (Folder 4)
          - 1969 January-March (Folder 5)
    - Seminars
      - Untitled (perhaps "Philosophy and Scientific Method"). Syllabi
        - 1964 February 11 (Box 380, Folder 1)
        - 1966 November 15 and 22 (Folder 2)
        - 1967 October 31 (Folder 3)
        - 1968
          - April 23 and 30 (Folder 4)
          - October 15 and 22 (Folder 5)
        - 1969 May 6 (Folder 6)
        - 1970 January 13 (Folder 7)
      - "Epistemology." Summary of discussion, 1950 February-April (Folder 8)
      - "Epistemology and Metaphysics." Bibliography, 1964-1965? (Folder 9)
      - "On Seeing Red." Syllabi, 1969
        - January 7 (Box 381, Folder 1)
        - January 14 (Folder 2)
      - "Philosophy and Scientific Method"
        - Attendance sheet, 1960-1961 (Folder 3)
        - Syllabi
          - 1964 October 12 (Folder 4)
          - 1965
            - June 28 (Folder 5)
            - October 11, 18, and 25 (Folder 6)
            - November 1 (Folder 7)
            - December 13. (Folder 8)
          - 1966
            - January 17 and 24 (Box 382, Folder 1)
            - January 31 (Folder 2)
            - February 7 (Folder 3)
            - March 21 (Folder 4)
      - "On the Third World." Notes and syllabus, 1968 December (Folder 5)
  - Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois. Notes for seminar held there, as well as at Harvard College, Cambridge, Massachusetts (Folder 6)
  - University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand. "Principles of Scientific Method," Lecture notes, 1937-1945. (Folder 7-8)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1945-1985 (Boxes 383-394)
  Curricula vitae, letters of recommendation, notes, correspondence, conference proceedings, minutes, reports, studies, manuals, rosters, directories, bylaws, programs, newsletters, circulars, brochures, clippings, and other printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Academie des Sciences Morales et Politiques (Box 383, Folder 1)
  - Academie Internationale de Philosophie des Sciences (Folder 2)
  - Academie Internationale d'Histoire des Sciences (Folder 3)
  - Acton, H. B. (Folder 4)
  - Adams, Walter (Folder 5)
  - Adler, Mortimer J. (Folder 6)
  - Agassi, Joseph. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, and Evans, Eve
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (Folder 8)
    - Letters of recommendation from Karl Popper (Folder 9)
  - Agassi, Judith (Folder 10)
  - Albert, Hans (Folder 11)
  - Alpbach European Forum (Folder 12)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Folder 13)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Folder 14)
  - Anstey, Vera (Folder 15)
  - Apostel, Leo (Folder 16)
  - Architecture. (Folder 17)
    Includes various letters to the editor re the Architectural Association symposium on decision-making organized by Royston S. Landau in 1963, as well as letters from Royston S. Landau to Karl Popper
  - Arendt, Hannah (Folder 18)
  - Aristotelian Society (Folder 19)
  - Aristotle (Folder 20)
  - Association for Symbolic Logic (Folder 21)
  - Association of University Teachers (Folder 22)
  - Austria (Folder 23)
  - Baird, E. A. B. (Folder 24)
  - Barkeley, Richard (Folder 25)
  - Bartley, William W., III
    - General (Box 384, Folder 1)
    - Letters of recommendation (Folder 2)
    - Reviews of his Retreat to Commitment (Folder 3)
  - Bedford College. (Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence with R. Mark Sainsbury and Mr. Carswell
  - Bell, John S. (Folder 5)
  - Beran, Michael F. (Folder 6)
  - Berkson, William K. (Folder 7)
    Includes notes on lectures by Karl Popper at Brandeis University, 1969, Fallsemester
  - Berlin, Isaiah (Folder 8)
  - Bertrand Russell Society (Folder 9)
  - Bharath, Professor (Folder 10)
  - Bhattacharya, Manju (Folder 11)
  - Biology (Folder 12)
  - Birner, Jack (Folder 13)
  - Blackmore, John T. (Folder 14)
  - Boehringer Ingelheim (Folder 15)
  - Bohm, David J. (Folder 16)
  - Bohr, Niels (Folder 17)
  - Boltzmann, Ludwig (Folder 18)
  - Boyle, Edward (Folder 19)
  - Bradley, Noel (Folder 20)
  - Brain. See also Computers (Folder 21)
  - Brehmer, Wilhelm von (Folder 22)
  - British Academy (Folder 23)
  - British Humanist Association (Folder 24)
  - British Society for the Philosophy of Science (Folder 25)
  - Broadhead, Henry Dan (Folder 26)
  - Broda, Engelbert (Folder 27)
  - Brooke-Wavell, Bruce (Folder 28)
  - Brouwer, L. E. J. (Folder 29)
  - Buhler, Karl (Folder 30)
  - Bunge, Mario (Folder 31)
  - Burgoyne, Bernard (Folder 32)
  - Burns, A. L. (Folder 33)
  - Carl Menger Institut (Box 385, Folder 1)
  - Carnap, Rudolf (Folder 2)
  - Chattopadhyaya, D. P. (Debi Prasad) (Folder 3)
  - Chelsea College (Folder 4)
  - Chemistry (Folder 5)
  - China (Folder 6)
  - Chomsky, Noam (Folder 7)
  - Clausius, R. (Folder 8)
  - Cleary, John J. (Folder 9)
  - Club Voltaire (Folder 10)
  - Cohen, Kalman Joseph (Folder 11)
  - Comite Martchenko. See CORRESPONDENCE, Bertrand Russell Society
  - Compton, Arthur Holly (Folder 12)
  - Computers (Folder 13)
  - Cooper, C. R. (Folder 14)
  - Cosmology. See also Kapp, Reginald O. (Folder 15)
  - Council for Science and Society (Folder 16)
  - Craik, Kenneth James William (Folder 17)
  - Critchley, Clive (Folder 18)
  - Cronin, Helena (Folder 19)
  - Cuban Missile Crisis, 1962 (Folder 20)
  - Darwin, Charles Robert (Folder 21)
  - Davies, John T. (Folder 22)
  - Dawe, Peter G. M. (Folder 23)
  - Dembeck, Richard C. (Folder 24)
  - Deutsche Physikalische Gesellschaft (Folder 25)
  - De Vries, G. J. (Folder 26)
  - Djilas, Milovan (Folder 27)
  - Djuric, Mihailo (Folder 28)
  - Eccles, John C. (Folder 29)
  - Eidlin, Fred H. (Folder 30)
  - Einstein, Albert (Folder 31)
  - Ellis, M. J. C. (Folder 32)
  - Elzinga, Aant (Folder 33)
  - Encyclopaedia Moderna (Folder 34)
  - Encyclopedia of Philosophy (Folder 35)
  - Eton College (Folder 36)
  - Evert William Beth Foundation (Folder 37)
  - Evolution (Folder 38)
  - Ewen, D. R. (Folder 39)
  - Falla, Robert Alexander (Box 386, Folder 1)
  - Farmand (Folder 2)
  - Farrell, Mr. (Folder 3)
  - Feigl, Herbert (Folder 4)
  - Fetzer, James H. (Folder 5)
  - Feyerabend, Paul. See alo CORRESPONDENCE, Evans, Eve (Folder 6)
  - Fields, Harvey (Folder 7)
  - Findlay, Allan F. (Folder 8)
  - Florence Center for the History and Philosophy of Science (Folder 9)
  - Foldes, Lucien P. (Folder 10)
  - Fong, Peter (Folder 11)
  - Fried, Lindy Bryony (Folder 12)
  - Fries, Dr. (Folder 13)
  - Furuseth, Conrad (Folder 14)
  - Gellner, Ernest (Folder 15)
  - Geometry (Folder 16)
  - Germany (Folder 17)
  - Giacomo, Piero de (Folder 18)
  - Giedymin, Jerzy (Folder 19)
  - Gillies, Donald A. (Folder 20)
  - Godel, Kurt (Folder 21)
  - Gombrich, Ernst H. (Folder 22)
  - Gomes da Costa, Brian L. (Folder 23)
  - Gosau, Peter (Folder 24)
  - Grayeff, Felix (Folder 25)
  - Greece (Folder 26)
  - Grunbaum, Adolf (Folder 27)
  - Guthrie, William Chambers Keith (Folder 28)
  - Haakonssen, Knud (Folder 29)
  - Habermehl, Werner (Folder 30)
  - Hamblin, Charles L. (Folder 31)
  - Hattiangadi, Jagdish N. (Folder 32)
  - Havayism (Folder 33)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Folder 34)
  - Hellegers, Andre E. (Folder 35)
  - Herder Correspondence (Folder 36)
  - Hernan, Francisco (Folder 37)
  - Hervey, Helen (Folder 38)
  - Hewitt, Derek (Folder 39)
  - Hobart, Robert H. (Folder 40)
  - Holgate, David John (Folder 41)
  - Horrobin, David F. (Folder 42)
  - Hudson, Henry (Folder 43)
  - Hull, David Lee (Folder 44)
  - Humanism (Folder 45)
  - Hutton, Gordon Milroy (Folder 46)
  - Imperialism (Folder 47)
  - International Congress of Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science (Folder 48)
  - International Congress of Philosophy (Folder 49)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 387, Folder 1)
  - International Federation of Institutes for Advanced Study (Folder 2)
  - International Institute for Advanced Study (Folder 3)
  - International Union of History and Philosophy of Science (Folder 4)
  - James, Catherine E. (Folder 5)
  - Jammer, Max (Folder 6)
  - Japan Prize (Folder 7)
  - Jarv, Harry (Folder 8)
  - Jarvie, Ian Charles (Folder 9)
  - Jung, Carl (Folder 10)
  - Kadlec, Erich (Folder 11)
  - Kahn, Charles H. (Folder 12)
  - Kapp, Reginald O. (Folder 13)
  - Karl Popper Centre at the London School of Economics (Folder 14)
  - Kaufmann, Felix (Folder 15)
  - Khamara, Edward J. (Folder 16)
  - Khan, R. F. (Folder 17)
  - King, Preston (Folder 18)
  - Kinzel, Augustus Brown (Folder 19)
  - Kment, Alfred (Folder 20)
  - Koertge, Noretta (Folder 21)
  - Koestenbaum, Peter (Folder 22)
  - Koestler, Arthur (Folder 23)
  - Kolakowski, Leszek (Folder 24)
  - Kolnai, Aurel T. (Folder 25)
  - Kordig, Carl R. (Folder 26)
  - Kovacevic, Vlado (Folder 27)
  - Kraft, Julius (Folder 28)
  - Kraus, Karl (Folder 29)
  - Kritischer Rationalismus und Sozialdemokratie, Vol. I, 1975, edited by Georg Luhrs, Thilo Sarrazin, Frithjof Spreer, and Manfred Tietzel (with an introduction by Helmut Schmidt, and writings and interviews of Karl Popper). Reviews, 1975-1976 (Folder 30)
  - Krol, Marcin (Folder 31)
  - Kron, A. (Folder 32)
  - Kunst, Paul (Folder 33)
  - Lai, Tyrone and Yen Ting (Box 388, Folder 1)
  - Lakatos, Imre (Folder 2)
  - Language (Folder 3)
  - League of Nations Covenant (Folder 4)
  - Leblanc, Hugues (Folder 5)
  - Lejewski, Czeslaw (Folder 6)
  - Letwin, Shirley Robin (Folder 7)
  - Levi, Isaac (Folder 8)
  - Levison, Arnold B. (Folder 9)
  - Lindsay, Fiona (Folder 10)
  - Lipscomb, William N. (Folder 11)
  - Llewelyn, John Edward (Folder 12)
  - Lob, M. H. (Folder 13)
  - London Mathematical Society (Folder 14)
  - London School of Economics. See also Adams, Walter, and Karl Popper Centre
    - General (Folder 15)
    - Calendars (Folder 16)
    - Lists of journals (Box 389, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 2)
    - Newsletters, 1981-1983 (Folder 3)
    - Reports by the Director, 1970 and 1979 (Folder 4)
    - Staff manual (Folder 5)
    - Timetables of courses and prospecti, 1945-1951 (Folder 6)
  - Lorenz, Konrad (Folder 7)
  - Lund, Pui-chong (Folder 8)
  - McGovern, George (Folder 9)
  - Magee, Bryan E. (Folder 10)
  - Marchi, Margaret (Folder 11)
  - Marcuse, Herbert (Folder 12)
  - Marshall, Trevor W. (Folder 13)
  - Marx, Karl (Folder 14)
  - Matrai, Laszlo (Folder 15)
  - Max-Planck-Gesellschaft (Folder 16)
  - Maxwell, Grover (Folder 17)
  - Medawar, Peter B. (Box 390, Folder 1)
  - Medical Hypotheses (Folder 2)
  - Medicine (Folder 3)
  - Metamedicine (Folder 4)
  - Milford-Hilferding, Peter (Folder 5)
  - Miller, David William
    - Correspondence (Folder 6)
    - Letters of recommendation (Folder 7)
    - Notes and corrections re various publications of Karl Popper (Folder 8)
  - Milne, Alan J. M. (Folder 9)
  - Mind (Folder 10)
  - Mind Association (Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 12-13)
  - Monod, Jacques (Folder 14)
  - Mont Pelerin Society
    - General (Folder 15)
    - Proceedings of the Seelisberg Conference, July 1949 (Folder 16)
  - Moon, Sun Myung (Folder 17)
  - Muller, Gert H. (Folder 18)
  - Muns, Joaquin (Folder 19)
  - Munz, Peter (Folder 20)
  - Musgrave, Alan Edward (Folder 21)
  - Music (Folder 22)
  - Mythology (Folder 23)
  - Nadad, Abraham (Box 391, Folder 1)
  - Neblett, William R., Jr. (Folder 2)
  - Newton, Isaac (Folder 3)
  - Novakovic, Stanisa (Folder 4)
  - Nuclear war (Folder 5)
  - Nuffield Foundation (Folder 6)
  - Ogassi, Dr. (Folder 7)
  - O'Gorman, James P. P. (Folder 8)
  - Open Society and Its Friends (Organization) (Folder 9)
  - Operations Research Society of America (Folder 10)
  - Oppenheim, Felix (Folder 11)
  - Orr, Robert R. (Folder 12)
  - Osterreichisches Ehrenzeichen fur Wissenschaft und Kunst. (Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence with Otto Kratky and Walter Brunner
  - Ozanne, K. W. (Folder 14)
  - Pacht, Otto (Folder 15)
  - Panikhar, Lila (Folder 16)
  - Papadaki, Irene (Folder 17)
  - Parikh, Suresh C. (Folder 18)
  - Passmore, John Arthur (Folder 19)
  - Paton, Alan Stewart (Folder 20)
  - Petersen, Arne Friemuth (Folder 21)
  - Philosophy (Folder 22)
  - Physics (Folder 23)
  - Plato (Folder 24)
  - Polanyi, Karl (Folder 25)
  - Pope, Neville Vivian (Folder 26)
  - Popkin, Richard H. (Folder 27)
  - Popper, Josefine (Folder 28)
  - Popper-Lynkens, Josef (Folder 29)
  - Post, Heinz R. (Folder 30)
  - Premdas, John A. Xavier (Folder 31)
  - Prior, Arthur N. (Folder 32)
  - Prior, W. E. (Folder 33)
  - Psychiatry (Folder 34)
  - Putnam, Hilary (Folder 35)
  - Quantum theory (Box 392, Folder 1)
  - Rand, Rose (Folder 2)